sanrio.com 2010-01-17

# Sanrio.com - Home of Hello Kitty

Updated on June 26, 2007.

#### PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THE SANRIO.COM SITE.

Sanrio, Inc. (" **Sanrio** ," " **we** ," " **us** ", " **our** ") provides www.sanrio.com (the " **Site** ").  We are committed to safeguarding all personal information we collect through our website and to explaining the choices you (" **users** ," " **you** " or " **your** ") can make about the collection and use of your personal information on or through the Site.  This Privacy Policy along with our [Terms of Use](http://www.sanrio.com/legal/terms.php) govern your interaction with the Site, and your registration for and use of the Site.  Except as set forth within this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use and other published guidelines, we do not release personally identifiable information about our users without their permission. 

#### 1\.      Introduction 

We do not collect any personally identifiable information unless you voluntarily provide it to us.  While you may use some of the functionality of the Site without registration, some of the activities and services might require you to subscribe or create an account.  If you do not subscribe or create an account on or through the Site, the only information we collect will be " **Non-Personal Information** " ( _i.e_., Information that is not traceable back to you and cannot be used to identify you.  Non-Personal Information includes information such as the web pages that you have viewed.) through the use of " **Cookies** " ( _i.e_., Small data files that are stored on the hard drive of a computer used to view web sites that are accessible only by the party or site that placed the Cookie on the hard drive.).  If you choose to subscribe or create an account through the Site, we may require you to submit " **Personally Identifiable Information** " ( _i.e._ , Information that can be traced back to you or used to identify you.  Personally Identifiable Information includes information such as your full name, home address, telephone number and e-mail address).  You are responsible for ensuring the accuracy of the Personally Identifiable Information you submit to Sanrio.  Inaccurate information will affect the information you receive when using the Site and tools and our ability to contact you.  For example, your e-mail address should be kept current because that is one of the primary means by which we are able to communicate with you.

#### 2\.      California Privacy Rights

Under California Law, California residents have the right to request in writing from businesses with whom they have an established business relationship, (a) a list of the categories of Personally Identifiable Information and the type of services provided to the customer, that a business has disclosed to third parties (including affiliates that are separate legal entities) during the immediately preceding calendar year for the third parties' direct marketing purposes, and (b) the names and addresses of all such third parties.  To request the above information, please e-mail us at:  privacystandards@sanrio.com, or write to us at:  Sanrio, Inc.; 570 Eccles Avenue; South San Francisco, CA 94080 with a reference to California Disclosure Information.

We will respond to such written requests within 30 days following receipt at the e-mail or mailing address stated above.  If we receive your request at a different e-mail or mailing address, we will respond within a reasonable period of time, but not to exceed 90 days from the date received.  Please note that we are only required to respond to each customer once per calendar year.

#### 3\.      Consent

BY SUBMITTING PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION TO US, AND/OR BY USING THE SITE, YOU AGREE THAT WE MAY COLLECT, USE AND DISCLOSE SUCH PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND TERMS OF USE, AND AS PERMITTED OR REQUIRED BY LAW.

If you do not agree with these terms, do not provide any Personally Identifiable Information to us.  If you refuse or withdraw your consent, or if you choose not to provide us with any required Personally Identifiable Information, we may not be able to provide you with products or services that can be offered on the Site only if we have access to certain Personally Identifiable Information.

#### 4\.      The Information We Gather

Sanrio gathers two types of information about users:

#### 4.1.   Non-Personal Information

When users come to the Site, we collect and aggregate Non-Personal Information indicating, among other things, which pages of the Site were visited, the order in which they were visited and which hyperlinks were "clicked."  Collecting such information involves the logging of the IP addresses, operating system and browser software used by each user to the Site. Although such information is not Personally Identifiable Information, we can determine from an IP address a user's Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of his or her point of connectivity. 

We also use Cookies to help us determine the type of content and sites to which a user to the Site links, the length of time each user spends at any particular area of the Site and the specific functionality that users choose to use.  Essentially, Cookies are a user's identification card for the Sanrio.com servers.  Cookies are only read by the server that placed them, and are unable to execute any code or virus.  Cookies allow us to serve you better and more efficiently, and to personalize your experience at the Site.  Cookies also may be used to facilitate a user's log-in, but are not used to retain Personally Identifiable Information.

You should be able to control how and whether Cookies will be accepted by your web browser.  Most browsers offer instructions on how to reset the browser to reject Cookies in the "Help" section of the toolbar.  If you reject our Cookies, certain of the functions and conveniences of the Site may not work properly, but you do not have to accept our Cookies in order to productively use the Site.

**(a) Google Analytics.**   This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

#### 4.2.   Personally Identifiable Information

We collect Personally Identifiable Information that you provide to us when you create an account, make purchases in our online store, subscribe to e-mail newsletters, send e-cards or e-mail to friends, participate in contents, sweepstakes and other promotions, or participate in online polls and surveys. 

**(a) Creating an Account.**   In order to make purchases or create a wish list in our online store, we will require you to create an account with us.  During this process, you will need to provide us with Personally Identifiable Information that may include, but may not be limited to, your first and last name, date of birth, mailing address, e-mail address, telephone number and password.  Sanrio will rely on you to self-report accurate information, and will not take steps to verify any information that you provide.

**(b) Making Purchases.**   When purchasing products or services through the Site, users are required to provide Sanrio with Personally Identifiable Information that may include, but may not be limited to, your first and last name, date of birth, mailing address, e-mail address, telephone number, credit card number and expiration date.  Sanrio uses this Personally Identifiable Information to process the order, send the product and/or provide the service.  If the purchase is a gift, we may also collect information about the recipient, such as name and mailing address. 

**(c) Subscribing to Newsletters**.  You may subscribe to the "Hello Kitty's Sweet Happy News" and other e-mail newsletters offered by us.  "Hello Kitty's Sweet Happy News" is a monthly (occasionally bi-monthly) newsletter e-mailed to subscribers. When you subscribe to our "Hello Kitty's Sweet Happy News" e-mail newsletter, we may ask for your first and last name, e-mail address, age, gender or favorite Sanrio character. 

**(d) Sending E-Cards and E-Mailing Art to a Friend.**  You can send an electronic postcard ("e-card") or e-mail to a friend using our Post Office.  We may ask for a first name and e-mail address, and we may also ask for personal information about the intended recipient, like a first name and e-mail address.

**(e) Participating In Contests, Sweepstakes and Other Promotions.**  From time to time, Sanrio may offer you the opportunity to participate in a contest, sweepstakes or other promotion through the Site.  If you desire to participate in any such contest, sweepstakes or other promotion, you will be asked to provide us with certain information necessary to conduct such contest, sweepstakes or other promotion.  This information may include, among other things, your name, age, mailing address, e-mail address and phone number.

**(f) Participating in Online Polls and Surveys.**   Sanrio may, from time to time, utilize online polls and/or surveys.  If you desire to participate in any such online poll or survey, you may be asked to provide us with Personally Identifiable Information, or you may be asked to provide only information that is not personally identifiable (such as first name only, city or state of residence, age, gender, or favorite Sanrio character).

#### 5\.      How We Use (and Do Not Use) the Information We Gather

Please take some time to familiarize yourself with the different ways Sanrio uses the information that we gather. 

#### 5.1. Non-Personal Information.

Sanrio uses Non-Personal Information primarily in aggregate form to build higher quality, more useful services by performing statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our users, and by measuring demographics and interests regarding specific areas of the Site.

#### 5.2. Personally Identifiable Information.

This Privacy Policy serves as notice that Sanrio collects Personally Identifiable Information in the manners described herein.  Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, Sanrio will not disclose any Personally Identifiable Information we gather from you on the Site.  Sanrio will release Personally Identifiable Information to third parties:  (a) to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order; or (b) in special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others.  In the event that we are legally compelled to disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to a third party, we will attempt to notify you unless doing so would violate the law or court order.  We cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who may be using our servers for illegal activities.  We also reserve the right to report any suspected illegal activity to law enforcement individuals or entities for investigation or prosecution.  In addition to the other uses set forth in this Privacy Policy, we may disclose and otherwise use Personally Identifiable Information as described below when you create an account, make purchases in our online store, subscribe to e-mail newsletters, send e-cards or e-mail to friends, participate in contents, sweepstakes and other promotions, or participate in online polls and surveys.

**(a) Creating an Account.**   Sanrio may use the Personally Identifiable Information that we collect from you when you create an account to contact you in connection with your use of the Site and to track who uses the various features and functionality offered at the Site.  Additionally, we may use this information in determining the types of features, functionality, products and services to offer through the Site or otherwise.

**(b) Making Purchases.**   Sanrio uses this Personally Identifiable Information collected during the purchasing process to fulfill the order, send the product and/or provide the service.

**(c) Subscribing to Newsletters.**   Sanrio uses contact information collected during subscription to send you the newsletter.

**(d) Sending E-Cards and E-Mailing Art to a Friend**.  When you provide information to send an e-card or e-mail to a friend, Sanrio will only use the information given to send the e-card or e-mail and will not retain the information once the e-card or e-mail is sent.

**(e) Participating In Contests, Sweepstakes and Other Promotions.**   Sanrio uses the Personally Identifiable Information, if any, it may collect from you related to a contest, sweepstakes or other promotion through the Site for processing purposes.  This Personally Identifiable Information will not be re-used, sold or shared in any manner by Sanrio or any third parties unless you elect to receive additional information and promotional material from Sanrio and/or third parties.  If a third party administers the contest, sweepstakes or other promotion, your participation may be subject to that third party's terms and conditions, and privacy policy.  Detailed information about these terms will be provided on the applicable form you will be asked to fill out.

**(f) Participating in Online Polls and Surveys.**   Sanrio may share aggregate information about our users with our advertising partners, such as that gathered from online polls or surveys.  We need to do this so that our advertising partners can target their advertisements at the right audiences.  Please however note that we do not give any personally identifiable information collected from users to any of our advertising partners.

**(g) Communications with Sanrio.**    
When you send an e-mail message to or otherwise contact Sanrio, Sanrio may use the information provided by you to respond to your communication and/or as described in this Privacy Policy.  Also, Sanrio may archive this information.

**(h) Disclosure to Sanrio Operations and Maintenance Contractors.**    
Sanrio operations and maintenance contractors sometimes have limited access to your Personally Identifiable Information in the course of providing products or services to Sanrio.  These contractors include vendors and suppliers that provide us with technology, services, and/or content related to better operation and maintenance of the Site.  Unless you have opted-out of receiving e-mails and newsletters from Sanrio, these contractors also may have access to your e-mail address to send newsletters to you on our behalf.  Access to your Personally Identifiable Information by these contractors is limited to the information reasonably necessary for the contractor to perform its limited function for Sanrio.  We also contractually require that our operations and maintenance contractors not use or disclose your Personally Identifiable Information for any purpose other than providing us with products and services, and that they secure your Personally Identifiable Information with safeguards equivalent to our own safeguards.

**(i) Purchase or Sale of Business.**    
From time to time, we may purchase a business or sell one or more of our businesses and your Personally Identifiable Information may be transferred as a part of the purchase or sale.  In the event that we purchase a business, the Personally Identifiable Information received with that business would be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy, if it is practicable and permissible to do so.  In the event that we sell a business, we will include provisions in the selling contract requiring the purchaser to treat your personally identifiable information in the same manner required by this Privacy Policy (including any amendments to this Privacy Policy).  In light of this protection, your opt-out choices described in this Privacy Policy will not affect our right to transfer your information to a purchaser in these circumstances.

**(j) Government Authorities; Legal Rights and Actions.**    
Sanrio may share your Personally Identifiable Information with various government authorities in response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law.  In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us.  We also may share your Personally Identifiable Information when we believe it is appropriate to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities; to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of the Site, our users, customers, or others; and in connection with our Terms of Use and other agreements.

#### **6.      Children's Privacy**

Sanrio requests that children consult with their parents before sending information to the Site.  We encourage parents to monitor their children's online activities, and to help us protect their privacy by instructing them never to provide their full name, address and other personal information without their parent's permission.  For more information on our privacy practices concerning children under the age of thirteen, please read the [Sanrio Children's Privacy Policy](http://www.sanrio.com/legal/parents.php). 

#### **7.      Linked Sites**

For your convenience there are links to web sites operated by companies other than Sanrio (" **Third Party Sites** ") that we believe may be of interest to you.  Sanrio does not disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to these Third Party Sites without obtaining your consent.  Sanrio does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices of these Third Party Sites.  If you choose to link to one of these Third Party Sites, you should carefully review the privacy policy posted on this other web site to understand how that Third Party Site collects and uses your Personally Identifiable Information.

#### **8.      Sanrio Security Procedures**

The security and confidentiality of your information is extremely important to us.  We have implemented technical, administrative, and physical security measures to protect your information from unauthorized access and improper use.  From time to time, we review our security procedures in order to consider appropriate new technology and methods.  Despite Sanrio's efforts to protect your Personally Identifiable Information, there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party may find a way around our security systems or that transmissions of your information over the Internet will be intercepted. 

**(a)** Sanrio requires both a personal username and a password in order for users to access their Personally Identifiable Information.

**(b)** Sanrio uses firewalls to protect information held in our servers.

**(c)** Sanrio utilizes Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption in transmitting Personally Identifiable Information to our servers.  In order to take advantage of encryption technology, you must have an Internet browser which supports 128-bit encryption.

**(d)** Sanrio closely monitors the limited number of Sanrio employees who have potential access to your Personally Identifiable Information.

**(e)** Sanrio backs-up our systems to protect the integrity of your Personally Identifiable Information.

#### **9.      Changes To This Privacy Policy**

Please note that Sanrio reviews its privacy practices from time to time, and that these practices are subject to change.  We ask that you bookmark and periodically review this web page to ensure continuing familiarity with the most current version of our Privacy Policy. 

#### **10.    International Users **

The Site is hosted in the United States and is intended for and directed to users in the United States.  If you access the Site from any region or country with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure, that differ from United States laws, please be advised that through your continued use of the Site, which is governed by U.S. law, this Privacy Policy, the Sanrio Children's Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use, you are transferring your personal information to the United States and you consent to that transfer. 

#### **11.    Accessing, Changing or Deleting Your Personally Identifiable Information**

If you want to (a) delete your Personally Identifiable Information from our systems, (b) update the Personally Identifiable Information that you have provided to us, or (c) change your preferences with respect to contacts or other activities, you can e-mail us at [webmaster@sanrio.com](mailto:webmaster@sanrio.com).  We try to promptly answer every e-mail, but may not always be able to do so.  Keep in mind, however, that there will be residual information that will remain within Sanrio databases, access logs and other records, which may or may not contain such personally identifiable information.  Sanrio reserves the right, from time to time, to recontact former users of the Site.

#### **12.   Questions, Comments or Concerns**

To contact Sanrio about privacy issues, to report a violation of our Privacy Policy, or to raise any other issue, please e-mail us at [privacystandards@sanrio](mailto:privacystandards@Sanrio.com).com.  You may also contact us at:  Sanrio, Inc.; 570 Eccles Avenue; South San Francisco, CA 94080, or call us at:  (650) 952-2880.

Before using this site, please also read our [Terms of Use](http://www.sanrio.com/legal/terms.php) and our [Children's Privacy Policy](http://www.sanrio.com/legal/parents.php).
